<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on TLDR Dev Notes</title>
    <link>localhost/hugo-tldr/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on TLDR Dev Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>TOML &amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="localhost/hugo-tldr/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Snippets</title>
      <link>localhost/hugo-tldr/misc/hugo_snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/hugo-tldr/misc/hugo_snippets/</guid>
      <description>Include a partial template partial {{ &amp;quot;foo.html&amp;quot; . }} partial {{ &amp;quot;foo&amp;quot; . }}   you use the partial function the partial directory is layouts &amp;gt; partials, this is where your partial templates will go templates are always .html files you don&amp;rsquo;t have to specify the file extension when including a partial template, Hugo knows it&amp;rsquo;s an html file {{ . }} represents the current context. {{ . }} always refers to the current context, meaning the data changes based on where it was used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Jekyll to Hugo</title>
      <link>localhost/hugo-tldr/webdev/move-jekyll-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/hugo-tldr/webdev/move-jekyll-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Why?  Jekyll is SLOW. Takes about 25 secs to build this site right now, and this site is pretty small right now, less than 500 posts. There are no tags or categories or pagination yet and it&amp;rsquo;s at 20 seconds already. I have to wait for it to finish in order to see any changes, and i make changes often, so i end up waiting often. Slow is pretty much my only complaint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Script to Convert Jekyll Front matter to Hugo</title>
      <link>localhost/hugo-tldr/jekyll/bash-script-to-convert-jekyll-front-matter-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/hugo-tldr/jekyll/bash-script-to-convert-jekyll-front-matter-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Changes  slug is now slug date (creation time) is now date lastmod (modification time) is now lastmod rename all collection folders to remove the underscore (_commands should now be commands) update filenames to remove date + add that date to post metadata remove layout:post from front matter (post metadata)  Find and update existing meta tags # Find and replace metadata tags grep -rl --null mtime . | xargs -0 sed -i &#39;&#39; &#39;s/mtime/lastmod/g&#39; grep -rl --null ctime .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>