<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sass on TLDR Dev Notes</title>
    <link>/tags/sass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sass on TLDR Dev Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>TOML &amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash script to create Media Queries with Sass</title>
      <link>/bash-scripting/bash_script_create_media_queries_sass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bash-scripting/bash_script_create_media_queries_sass/</guid>
      <description>The following bash script will create a main sass stylesheet style.scss and then create additional sass stylesheets for all devices (mobile.scss, ipad.scss, desktop.scss, wide.scss, iphone.scss) in a folder called media-queries.
In the end, we will combine stylesheets for all devices into one by importing them into our main style.scss.
I have divided the code for different devices in their own stylesheets becuase it keeps it is neat and organized and i prefer it that way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Sass</title>
      <link>/css-sass/debug-troubleshoot-sass-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 06:08:52 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/css-sass/debug-troubleshoot-sass-issues/</guid>
      <description>sass --help OR sass -h OR sass -? will give you a whole list of commands you can use and how to use them.
sass --style compressed main.css will output a compressed version of main.css in the console.
sass --style compressed main.css:main.css the file before the : is the input file and the one after is the output file.
sass --style expanded main.css:main.css converts to &amp;lsquo;expanded&amp;rsquo; style, which is nested but without the indentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sass: Working with Libraries</title>
      <link>/css-sass/howto-sass-work-with-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 20:13:51 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/css-sass/howto-sass-work-with-libraries/</guid>
      <description>By far the most popular Sass based UI framework is Bootstrap. Another one is Foundation.
Sass libraries are more like a collection of mixins, funtcions and classes. The most common is Compass. Then there is Bourbon.
Installing Bourbon sudo gem install bourbon  Including Bourbon in a Project just include the bourbon .scss file in the main stylesheet.
@import &amp;quot;bourbon_bourbon.scss&amp;quot;;  Benefits  You can use all the new CSS3 features without having to worry about backwards compatibility as Bourbon and Compass take care of adding vendor prefixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Files in Sass with `@import`</title>
      <link>/css-sass/howto-sass-import-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 19:51:45 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/css-sass/howto-sass-import-files/</guid>
      <description>Importing files is handy when you have your css in multiple files instead of one bloated stylesheet. See Bootstrap&amp;rsquo;s Sass files for an example. Every css component gets it&amp;rsquo;s own .scss file and they all get compiled into one main stylesheet.
The usual imports in a main.scss file are something like this:
// Reset @import &amp;quot;_reset.scss&amp;quot;; // Definings @import &amp;quot;_varables.scss&amp;quot;; @import &amp;quot;_mixins.scss&amp;quot;; // Global Styles @imprt &amp;quot;_globals.scss&amp;quot;; // Page specifics @import &amp;quot;pages/_about_us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Color Palette in Sass</title>
      <link>/css-sass/howto-sass-create-a-color-palette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 19:26:53 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/css-sass/howto-sass-create-a-color-palette/</guid>
      <description>$background: #f3f3f3; $text_color: #888; $link_color: #; $primary_color: mix(#ff0000, #fefefe); $secondary_color: complement($primary_color); $highlighted_text_color: darken($text_color, 30%);  Light and Dark shades Get a darker shade color: darken($text_color, 20%);  OR
color: darken(#888, 20%)  will give you a 20% darker shade of $text_color or #888. If you use a variable, it&amp;rsquo;ll change the colors dynamically, meaning the light/dark shade will vary with the base color variable used.
Get a lighter shade color: lighten($text_color, 20%);  OR</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Compass on a Mac via Command Line</title>
      <link>/css-sass/howto-sass-install-compass-on-a-mac-via-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 15:34:28 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/css-sass/howto-sass-install-compass-on-a-mac-via-command-line/</guid>
      <description>Compass is a Ruby gem, so in order to install it you must have Ruby installed. Macs come pre-installed with Ruby.
sudo gem update --system sudo gem install compass compass --version  Notes  sudo gem update --system will make sure all gems are up to date You can use sass --version to see if you have installed or what version of Sass is it sudo gem install compass will also install Sass if it isn&amp;rsquo;t already installed compass --version will confirm the installation by telling you what version of Compass you have installed If command line scares you, you can install GUI apps for Compass, like:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>