<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on TLDR Dev Notes</title>
    <link>/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on TLDR Dev Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>TOML &amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Code for Humans to Read</title>
      <link>/programming/human-readable-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/human-readable-code/</guid>
      <description>Programs are meant to be read by humans and only incidentally for computers to execute. - Donald Knuth
  Write your code for humans, humans are the ones who&amp;rsquo;ll read, maintain and improve it. Computers only get machine code, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it. Whitespace is amazing when done right Be consistent. Be consistent in your naming, in capitalization, in spacing, in indentation, in code style. Pick a style, and stick to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Tmux</title>
      <link>/programming/tmux-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/tmux-basics/</guid>
      <description>brew install tmux install tmux with homebrew (macOS) tmux open tmux exit or Ctrl+D to close a pane, exit tmux  tmux is controlled by a key combination of a prefix key, &amp;lsquo;C-b’ Ctrl-b by default, followed by a command key.
 ctrl+B, then ? to open a list of all key bindings ctrl+B, then % to open a new pane (horizontal) ctrl+B, then &amp;quot; (double-quote) to open a pane (vertical) ctrl+B, then arrow key (left/right/up/down) to move between panes (horizontal)  Links  Egghead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scope</title>
      <link>/programming/scope-in-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/scope-in-programming/</guid>
      <description> Scope  where to look for things
 Notes  JavaScript is a compiled language. It is compiled everytime it is run (i.e. compiled at runtime) JavaScript has only function scope atm.  Links  Frontend Masters: Advanced JavaScript - Scope  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursion</title>
      <link>/programming/recursion-in-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/recursion-in-programming/</guid>
      <description>Recursion A recursive function is a function which calls itself.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how it goes: beginning recursion -&amp;gt; recursive loop of repeating a task -&amp;gt; until we hit our base case.
 a function being defined is applied within its own definition. While this apparently defines an infinite number of instances (function values), it is often done in such a way that no loop or infinite chain of references can occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Higher Order Functions</title>
      <link>/programming/higher-order-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/higher-order-functions/</guid>
      <description>Higher-order Functions - Any complicated function that was composed by combining simple functions is a higher order function. - Functions that operate on other functions, either by taking them as arguments or by returning them, are called higher-order functions. - Eloquent JavaScript - A higher-order function is a function that takes other functions as arguments and/or returns a function as it&#39;s result. - Wikipedia  Notes  Functions are values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packages and Dependencies</title>
      <link>/programming/packages-and-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/packages-and-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>They call it package, because many times you would have a collection of libraries that are packaged together, and you download that package rather than each individual library. As for dependency, many times a package will depend on another package, and the dependency manager can help solve that problem.
A dependency manager also takes care of versioning and package updates.
Each programming language has it&amp;rsquo;s own flavor of dependency manager. For instance, for Javascript Node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>